- [Tutor] We've added
the ability for our enemy
to spawn at random
positions on our screen.
Now, we're going to do just
a bit more code clean up
and teach you something new about
creating your own custom methods.
In our spawn manager script,
we have in our Start method,
a way to create a position
for each of our enemies.
Now, in the past we've made our
own custom functions before,
so we're going to do that again.
Now, we're going to make this
a private method, so that way,
we only need to use this
method inside of this class,
so we don't need it anywhere else really.
For now, we're going to
make this a void method,
so it doesn't really do
anything, except tell us things.
We're going to call it
GenerateSpawnPosition.
And then we can just leave the parentheses
because we're not actually
passing it any information,
it's just going to do something.
So now, in our GenerateSpawnPosition,
we're actually just
going to use this code,
so that we can create
our own spawn position.
So if we control or
command x, and we paste it
into our GenerateSpawnPosition.
So now you can see our random
position is mad at us for now,
but that's fine.
So what this is gonna do, is
enter GenerateSpawnPosition.
When we call this in our
scripts and our update,
it'll create a random
spawn position for us.
So it'll create this random X position,
it'll create this random Z position.
And then, it will store those numbers
into a random position, which is great,
except the problem is, it
doesn't actually do anything
from there, it just does this calculation,
gives us a random coordinate
and then it doesn't actually
do anything with the coordinate.
Now, this is a key difference
between using void functions,
and return type functions.
So a void function, you
use for a specific tasks
that you do not need to return a value.
For example, in one of
our previous lessons,
we actually used a spawn
method using the void keyword.
Now in that case, we just wanted to create
a random object on the
screen and that's all that
that method did.
However, when we actually use
methods that return a value,
we do it for the purpose
of giving us information
after a calculation.
So GenerateSpawnPosition,
actually gives us a position
that we need to use.
So, we take out the void keyword
and we put in the specific
type of data that we want
to come out of this method.
In this case, we go from
a void to a Vector3.
Now, you can see that
our program is mad at us
because this doesn't return a value.
Fortunately, we have a value here,
we have a Vector3 that we've already made.
But now, we need this
Vector3 to actually come out
and result from this method.
So, if we actually type
in the keyword return,
we can return our random position.
So now, when we actually
go into our Start method,
where we had the random position before,
we can actually now just call
generate random position.
So now in our Instantiate method,
it's no longer unhappy with us.
That's because, in place
of our random position,
when we call GenerateSpawnPosition,
it actually outputs or
returns a random Vector3
that we need.
So, in specific cases, where
we're actually trying to get
some kind of data out of our methods,
we can use return types, to
actually get that data back
from that method.
Now, it's a very confusing concept,
the difference between Vector3's and voids
but over time, as you use them more
and understand how you're
supposed to use them,
it gets a lot easier.
So now you can see when we go
into our game and press play,
it spawns a random enemy
in a random position.
If we press play again, it spawns it
in another random position once again.
So what you're gonna do, in
your spawn manager script,
you're going to create
a new private method
and instead of void, like you
can see in Update or Start,
we're going to actually put Vector3
and we're gonna call this
GenerateSpawnPosition.
And then we take all the code that we use
to generate random positions
on the X and the Z.
We then take our vector
variable that we've created
and then we use the word
return and we return
that variable that we've made so that way
when we use our instantiate method
or GenerateSpawnPosition,
will actually give us
a Vector3 that we can then use
as part of this entire line of code.
Now it's your turn.
(upbeat sound)